あぁっ！
え～っ！ ﾃﾚﾋﾞどこ!?
(いびき)
Boom!
Wh-What?!
Watch TV in a well-lit room and
don't sit too close to the screen.
Huh?! Where's the TV?!
♪♪～
Oof.
[OTOSE SNACK HOUSE]
(あくび)
(お登勢)おはよう たま｡
Good morning, Tama.
(たま)おはようございます
お登勢様｡
Good morning, Otose-sama.
ﾊｧｰ｡ ﾎﾝﾄ ｱﾝﾀは
ｷｬｻﾘﾝと違って働きもんだねぇ｡
Unlike Catherine, you work very hard.
毎日 毎日
こんなに朝早くから せっせと…｡
Making yourself busy bright
and early every morning...
もうちょっと
寝てたっていいんだよ｡
You could sleep in a little
longer, you know.
We don't open till nighttime.
どうせ店開くの 夜なんだからさ｡
(たま)私にとって睡眠は
体力補給の意味を成しません｡
In my case, sleep does not serve as
a method of replenishing my energy.
少しの充電とｵｲﾙさえあれば
活動に支障はありませんので➡
I can function normally on only
a little recharge and oil.
お気になさらないでください｡
So please do not concern yourself.
役に立ってないようで
役に立ってるのが睡眠ってもんさ｡
Sleep is the kind of thing that's
beneficial without feeling like it is.
人間も機械も 頭空っぽにして
休む時間てのが必要だろう｡
People and machines need time
to rest and clear their minds.
ﾊｧｰ｡
食って寝て遊ぶ…
そういう当たり前のことが➡
Eat, sleep, and play.
The things we take for granted are
more important than you think.
実は最も大切なことなんだよ｡
そういう基礎が ｶﾞﾀついてくると➡
If you don't maintain a stable foundation,
上の連中みたいに
なにかっちゃ ｶｾﾞひいたり➡
you'll end up like those losers upstairs.
Catching colds all the time,
腹くだしたり 年がら年中
調子悪いっていうはめになんだよ｡
upsetting their stomachs,
feeling under the weather
all year round...
からくりが
ｶｾﾞをひくことはありません｡
A robot can't catch a cold.
お気になさらないでください｡
Please do not concern yourself.
ｶｾﾞはないだろうけどさ ｱﾝﾀ
どっか調子悪いとことかないの？
You won't catch a cold,
but aren't you feeling a little
under the weather?
最近 働きづめじゃないのさ｡
たまには温泉… がﾀﾞﾒなら➡
You've been working non-stop
the past few days.
An occasional trip to a hot springs...
Won't work, but how about
soaking yourself in oil?
ｵｲﾙにでも
浸かりに行ったらどうなのさ｡
お登勢様｡
Otose-sama.
ありがとうございます…
いつも気にかけてくださって｡
Thank you very much for always
being concerned about me.
でも本当に大丈夫です｡
But I'm truly fine.
私は こうして
みなさんと一緒に働けるだけで…｡
The fact that I'm able to work
here with everyone...
こうして みなさんと
一緒にいられるだけで…｡
The fact that I can be
here with everyone...
ｼｱﾜｾﾃﾞｽｶﾗ｡
Is enough to make me happy.
["Smooth Polygons Smooth Men's Hearts Too"]
(銀時)あ？
たまの様子がおかしい？
Eh? Something's wrong with Tama?
うん｡ ｱﾀｼの
見間違えかもしれないけどさ➡
Yes... It may have just been
the light playing tricks on me,
but her face looked odd for a moment.
顔が一瞬 変なふうに見えて…｡
顔が一瞬 変？
Her face looked odd for a moment?
四六時中 変なｱﾝﾀよりﾏｼだろう｡
そうね｡
Better than looking odd 24/7.
That's right.
四六時中 ｾﾐの抜け殻みたいな
顔してるｱﾝﾀよりﾏｼなんだけどさ｡
It beats having a face that looks like
a cicada husk 24/7 the way you do.
ひと昔前の格闘ｹﾞｰﾑみたいな➡
It reminded me of those fighting games
from a while back, all jagged...
ｶｸｶｸしてる…
あれ 何ていうんだっけ？
What were they called again?
ﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝ？
あ そうそう｡
Polygons?
Yes, yes. Her face was all jagged
like it was made of polygons.
ﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝみたいな
ｶｸｶｸした顔になっててさぁ｡
あの子 きっと
働きすぎて疲れてんのよ｡
I'm sure she's tired after working so hard.
ｱﾝﾀ ちょっと 故障してないか
見てやってくれないかい？
Could you check if any screws
are loose or anything?
その前に
ｱﾝﾀの頭が故障してないか➡
First, you should go see a doctor
for the screws loose in your head.
医者に診てもらったほうが
いいだろ｡
どんな壊れ方したら
からくりが ﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝになるんだよ｡
How could a little breakdown make
a puppet look like polygons?
なんで 機械が疲れるんだよ｡
How could a machine get tired?
あたしゃ ﾎﾝﾄに見たんだよ｡
I saw it with my own eyes.
((ｱ… ｱﾝﾀ… その顔 いったい？
H-Hey...
What's with your face...
ﾅﾝﾃﾞｼｮｳｶ？
いや ｶｸｶｸだよ！
What do you mean?
No, it's all jagged.
顔だけじゃなくて 全身ｶｸｶｸに…｡
ｽﾐﾏｾﾝ｡
Not just your face. Your
whole body's all jagged!
I am sorry. I cannot comprehend
what Otose-sama is saying.
ｵﾄｾｻﾏｶﾞ ﾅﾆｦ ｵｯｼｬｯﾃｲﾙﾉｶ
ﾖｸﾜｶﾘﾏｾﾝ｡
いや わかるだろ！ ﾊﾟｯと見れば
それ すぐわかるよ！))
No, this should be easy to understand!
It's in plain sight!
最近 あの子 働きすぎだしさ
心配なんだよ｡
She has worked too hard
the past few days.
I was worried, so I kept telling
her to take a break.
休め休めって言ってるのにさ｡
It was probably an optical illusion.
目の錯覚だよ｡
そんなｱﾎな話 あるわけねえだろ｡
Something that ridiculous
could never happen.
疲れてるのは ｱﾝﾀのほうだ｡
お迎えが ちけえんだよ｡
You're the one who's tired.
Your time's coming.
(たま)ただ今 帰りました｡
I have returned.
おかえり おつかい ご苦労さ…｡
Welcome back. Thanks for...
Ah, Master Gintoki.
Good morning.
Forget polygons!
She's down to pixels now!
(新八)ﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝどころか
ﾄﾞｯﾄ絵まで退化してますけど！
Tama completed her errand.
230 experience gained.
300 G lost.
ふきだしまで
ﾌｧﾐｺﾝ並みのｽﾍﾟｯｸに落ちてるよ！
Even the speech bubbles
are NES-level!
Otose-sama.
Sorry for the wait.
The supermarket was crowded
because of a sale.
しかも 前後左右
どこに移動しても ｶﾆ歩きの➡
And she's facing forward regardless of
the direction she's moving, like a crab!
初代ﾄﾞﾗｸｴ仕様ですよ！
気持悪いよ！
The way it was in the first Dragon Quest!
It's creepy!
ﾗﾀﾞﾄｰﾑの悲しげな曲
流れてきそうだよ！
I can hear that sad song they
played in Radatom Castle!
Here, Otose-sama.
These are the goods you requested.
Tama handed over a medicinal herb.
[Note: This is a reference to a famous
line from Dragon Quest.]
There is no response. It's just a corpse.
誰が しかばねだ！
Who are you calling a "corpse"?!
And I never asked for medicinal herbs!
つ～か 薬草なんて
誰も頼んでないっつ～の！
Tama handed over a cypress stick.
それも頼んでねえ！ つ～か
どこの道具屋行ってきた！
I didn't ask for that either!
Which item store did you even go to?!
There is no response.
It's just a corpse.
ごまかすな！
Don't try to play dumb!
Tama-san!
たまさ～ん！
なんで こんなことに!?
How did you end up like this?!
いったい 何が
あったっていうんですか！
What in the world happened?!
あぁ ごめんよ たま｡
I'm so sorry, Tama!
You must have broken down because
I worked you too hard!
私が ﾑﾘに お前を
働かせ続けたばかりに➡
故障しちまったんだね…｡
Gin-chan, fix her already.
(神楽)銀ちゃん 直してあげなよ｡
こんなｶｸｶｸじゃ 危ないね｡
刺さるｱﾙ｡
It's dangerous when she's
all jagged like this.
People will cut themselves.
お子さまの安全面を考慮しても➡
You should fix her into a form that's
completely round and child safe.
丸みを帯びたﾌｫｰﾑに
直したほうがいいｱﾙ｡
別に いいんじゃねえ？
このままでも｡
What's wrong with leaving her like this?
前と たいして変わらねえし｡
変わるだろ！ 見てくださいよ！
There isn't that much difference.
Hell yes, there is!
Just look!
黙ってても その場で
足踏みしちゃうんですよ！
Her legs are still moving while
she's quietly standing here!
右足と左足 交互に振り下ろす
２ﾊﾟﾀｰﾝしか絵柄ないんですよ｡
She only has two available poses,
one with her right leg up and
one with her left leg up!
大丈夫だよ｡ ﾛｰﾗ姫助けたあとは➡
It'll be fine.
She'll get the pose where
姫を抱きかかえるﾊﾟﾀｰﾝの絵も
加わるから｡
she's carrying a princess after
she rescues Princess Laura.
[Note: Refers to Princess Laura
from Dragon Quest game.]
ﾛｰﾗ姫なんて
この世界に存在しねえよ！
Princess Laura doesn't exist in this world!
見た目はともかく もともと
これくらい使えないﾔﾂだったろ｡
Appearances aside, she
was always this useless.
別にいいじゃん このまんまで｡
Who cares if she stays this way?
そもそも お前ら若い世代は➡
Besides, you young'uns are too
used to CG and 3D rendering.
やれＣＧだ やれ３Ｄﾓﾃﾞﾘﾝｸﾞだのに
慣れすぎなんだよ｡
ﾄﾞｯﾄ絵くらいが
ちょうどいいんだよ｡
Pixels are classic.
いや なんの話をしてるんですか？
Uh, what are you talking about?
ｵﾚたちの時代なんかな
単純な線だけで描かれたﾀﾞﾝｼﾞｮﾝを➡
Back in our day, we couldn't
wait to explore dungeons
それでも ﾜｸﾜｸしながら
探索してたもんだ｡
that consisted of just straight lines.
美麗なＣＧこそねえが➡
There wasn't any pretty CG, but we
let our imaginations run the show.
だからこそ そこに
無限の想像の余地があった｡
Uh, so what are you talking about?
いや だから
なんの話をしてるんですか？
Sure, the first time I turned the power on,
そりゃ 最初は
ﾊﾟｯｹｰｼﾞのかっけえ絵と➡
電源入れたときのｷﾞｬｯﾌﾟに
がっかりしたよ｡
I was a little disappointed with the flashy cover
art not matching the actual in-game screens.
こんなもんかと思ったよ｡
I was like, that's it?
But by the time I reached the ending
credits, I felt like I was the hero!
けど 晴れて
ｴﾝﾃﾞｨﾝｸﾞﾛｰﾙを迎えたときには➡
もう 勇者は自分ですよ｡
ｷｬｽﾄは あなたに感無量だよ｡
いや だから なんの…｡
I was so touched when I saw the
word "you" in the cast credits.
Uh, what are you...
それを 最近のﾔﾂは➡
But nowadays, they play these
long-ass CG cut scenes.
ﾀﾞﾗﾀﾞﾗ長ったらしい ＣＧﾑｰﾋﾞｰ
垂れ流しにしやがって｡
ｵﾚたちは 映画が観たいのか？
違うだろ➡
Are we trying to watch a movie?
No, right?
We want to play a game!
ｹﾞｰﾑがやりたいんだろうが！
違うわ！ どっからｹﾞｰﾑの話に
すり替わったんだ！
No!
How did this turn into a discussion
about gaming?!
Got it?
いいか？ ｹﾞｰﾑは
やらされるもんじゃねえ➡
Games don't play you! You play games!
やるもんなんだ｡
ＣＧも ﾑｰﾋﾞｰもいらねえ！
We don't need any CG or movies!
そんなもんに 踊らされてっから➡
You wanna let them lead you around?!
ﾃﾒｴら 想像力が貧困なんだよ｡
Do you have no imagination?!
Pixel graphics!
ｸﾞﾗﾌｨｯｸは ﾄﾞｯﾄ
ｲﾍﾞﾝﾄは ﾃｷｽﾄのみで進行！
Events that are text-only!
That's all you need!
それで 十分なんだ！
That's enough. Just shut up.
もういい 黙ってろよ｡
ｳｨｻﾞｰﾄﾞﾘｨ世代は 村正求めて➡
The Wizardry generation can go scour
their dungeons for Muramasa.
[Note: Wizardry was a 1980s game. Swords
named Muramasa often show up in games.]
迷宮奥地を さまよってろ｡
どうせ 直す自信ないんでしょ？
You probably don't think you can fix her.
わかりました もう頼みませんよ｡
I get it. I won't ask you.
情けないｱﾙ｡ ＤＶＤの配線
出来ない男くらい 情けないｱﾙ｡
Pathetic.
As pathetic as a man who can't
hook up a DVD player.
ｺﾞｷﾌﾞﾘ見て ｷｬｰとか叫ぶ男くらい
情けないｱﾙ｡
As pathetic as a man who screams
when he sees a cockroach.
いまだに ﾏﾐｰに ﾊﾟﾝﾂ選んで
買ってきてもらってる男くらい➡
As pathetic as a man who still has
his mommy buy his underwear.
情けないｱﾙ｡
ﾎﾝﾄ➡
Seriously, what's with the adults
who get all nostalgic
ｹﾞｰﾑの話になると すぐ
懐古主義になる大人は➡
when they start talking about games?
どうかと思うよね｡
Tama handed over a medicinal herb.
なに 気遣ってんだ！
Why are you trying to be nice to me?!
What kind of wounds am I supposed
to heal with that?!
ｵﾚに それで
何の傷を癒やせというんだ!?
おい あんまり ｳｨｻﾞｰﾄﾞﾘｨ世代
ﾅﾒてんじゃねえぞ｡
Hey, you shouldn't look down
on the Wizardry generation.
直そうと思えばな こんなもん
一瞬で直せんだよ｡
I could fix this in a second if I wanted to.
わかった｡ お前らが
そこまで言うなら わかった｡
Fine. If you're gonna be that way, fine.
ｵﾚが 直してやるよ｡
ﾎﾝﾄｱﾙか？
I'll fix her.
Really?
見とけよ ﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝ世代｡
Just watch, polygon generation.
ｳｨｻﾞｰﾄﾞﾘｨ世代の力を
見せつけてやるよ｡
I'll show you the power of
the Wizardry generation.
ん？ あれ？ 何すか？ この画面｡
Huh? What's with the screen?
[Ow!]
[Camp]
[Organize]
[Repair]
[Leave]
[Investigate]
[Gintoki]
[Patsuan]
[Kagura]
[Old Lady]
[A dark and musty room.]
[There are bottles rolling on the floor.]
[It appears this place was once a bar.]
[A glance into the center of the room
reveals a person amongst the bottles.]
[No, a broken puppet doll is lying on the floor.]
[A glance into the center of the room
reveals a person amongst the bottles.]
[No, a broken puppet doll is lying on the floor.]
[Help it up and repair it?]
[Yes / No]
[The puppet doll was successfully repaired!!]
All right!
おっしゃ～！
って 何も直ってねえだろうが！
You didn't fix anything!
なに ｳｨｻﾞｰﾄﾞﾘｨ風に ﾃｷｽﾄのみで
ｲﾍﾞﾝﾄ進行して➡
Why are you trying to go through
events text-only like in Wizardry?!
ごまかそうとしてんの！
You think it's okay to use
only text in an anime?!
ｱﾆﾒが ﾃｷｽﾄのみで
進んでいいと思ってんの!?
画面もたねえだろうが！
直るわけねえだろ そんなんで！
The screen won't last!
You can't fix anything like that!
どうやって直したか 視聴者に
想像の余地を与える➡
I gave the viewers the freedom
to imagine how she was fixed.
それが ｳｨｻﾞｰﾄﾞﾘｨ流だ｡
That's the Wizardry way.
ただ手抜いただけだろ
お前は！
You're just being lazy!
つうか 直ってねえし！
もういいよ！
And she isn't fixed!
Forget it!
ｳｨｻﾞｰﾄﾞﾘｨ世代は 教会で
蘇生に失敗して 灰になれ！
The Wizardry generation can go
and fail to resurrect at a church
and turn to ashes!
Zip it, polygon generation!
黙れ！ ﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝ世代！
教会で 蘇生に失敗して➡
Fail to resurrect at a church and
turn into powdered polygons!
ﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝ 粉々になれ！
うっさい！
Shut up!
岩の中にﾃﾚﾎﾟｰﾄして
ﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰ全滅しろ！
Teleport into a rock and
wipe out the party!
お前が ﾎﾟﾘｺﾞﾝの中にﾃﾚﾎﾟｰﾄして➡
You teleport into polygons and live
on for me as a Virtua Fighter!
一生 ﾊﾞｰﾁｬﾌｧｲﾀｰとして
ｵﾚの分まで生きろ！
[Mechanic's Shop]
(源外)う～ん こりゃ ｶｾﾞだなぁ｡
She's got a cold.
ｶｾﾞ!? からくりが ｶｾﾞひくって
どういうことですか？
A cold?
How can a robot catch a cold?
正確に言えば 電脳ｳｲﾙｽに
感染しとる｡
It would be more accurate to say that
she's caught a computer virus.
電脳ｳｲﾙｽ？
うむ｡
A computer virus?
電脳空間をさまようﾃﾞｰﾀや
ﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑを破壊する不正ﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑよ｡
An illegal program that roams the
virtual world destroying data.
おおかた 事務仕事をこなすため➡
She was probably infected when she connected
to the Internet for her work.
ﾈｯﾄに回路をつなげた際に
侵入されて 感染したんだろう｡
じゃあ その 電脳ｳｲﾙｽのせいで
たまさんは ﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑを破壊され➡
So the computer virus has destroyed
Tama-san's program,
こうして 不調を起こしていると？
うむ｡
which is why she's behaving this way.
おいおい ようやく ｵﾚたちが
ｶｾﾞ治ったと思ったら➡
Hey now.
We finally recovered from our colds,
今度は ｺｲﾂか｡
じいさん たま直るよね？
and now this?
Old geezer, you can fix Tama, right?
元に戻るよね？
You can put her back to normal, right?
う～ん… 普通のｳｲﾙｽなら➡
A commercial anti-virus program would
be enough to deal with ordinary viruses,
市販のｳｲﾙｽﾊﾞｽﾀｰで 駆除できるが➡
ｺｲﾂについてるのは ちと
厄介なﾔﾂでな｡
but she's got an especially tough one.
電脳ｳｲﾙｽ ｢獏｣｡
The computer virus "Tapir."
A brand-new virus that infects the program,
consumes it, and multiplies.
ﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑにとりつき
それを喰らうように➡
増殖肥大化する 最新型ｳｲﾙｽ｡
獏は 宿主である
からくりｼｽﾃﾑの情報を取り込み➡
Tapir reads the data from
the system it has infected
自身のﾌﾟﾛｸﾞﾗﾑをも 書き換えていく｡
while rewriting its own program.
It evolves, becoming more
efficient as it multiplies
より効率的に 増殖できるように➡
より 駆除されないように
自身を 強化成長していく｡
and more deeply embedded in its victim.
故に 寄生したばかりの獏であれば
対抗策もあるが➡
A Tapir infection caught early
on can be easily dealt with,
長くとりつき成長した獏を
駆除するのは難しい｡
but one that's been evolving over an extended
period will be more difficult to remove.
加えて獏は 寄生したｼｽﾃﾑが
高度であればあるほど➡
And the Tapir virus will be as strong
as the system it has infected.
その能力を高める｡
Once it infected Tama, who
is a highly advanced robot,
超高度なからくり技術を施された
たまに侵入した時点で➡
相当に育ったﾔﾂだったんだろうが
更に そこに長く潜伏したんだ｡
it must have evolved a great deal.
And it's been there for a while.
Nobody can do anything about it.
もはや 誰の手にも負えねえ
最悪最強のｳｲﾙｽになっていようよ｡
It's evolved into the strongest
and worst virus ever.
そんな…｡ 源外さんでも どうにも
ならないっていうんですか？
N-No way...
Even you, Gengai-san, can't fix her...
Don't be ridiculous.
ﾊﾞｶ言っちゃいけねえ｡
ｵﾚは
江戸一番のからくり技師だぞ｡
I'm the top robot technician in Edo.
やれねえことはねえ｡
There's nothing I can't do.
だが なにせ最新型のｳｲﾙｽ｡
However...
We're dealing with a brand-new virus.
ﾜｸﾁﾝ作るにも時間がかかる｡
It'll take some time to make a vaccine.
By the time I finish, Tama will have
been completely consumed.
仕事終えた頃にゃ たまの中身は➡
ﾔﾂに食い尽くされた
空っぽの抜け殻｡
She'll be a robot with no soul.
魂の抜けた
ただの人形になっちまうだろうよ｡
そんな｡
No way...
だが まだ一つだけ
たまを助ける方法がある｡
But there's still a way to save Tama.
なんだ｡ 言ってみろ じいさん｡
What?
Let us hear it, old geezer.
危険な賭けになるぞ｡
たまにとっても ﾃﾒｴらにとっても｡
It'll be a dangerous gamble.
For Tama...
And for all of you...
かまわねえ 早く言え｡
It doesn't matter.
Just tell us.
その言葉 たまのために
命かけてもいいと➡
Should I interpret that response to mean
that you're willing to risk
your lives for Tama?
とっていいんだな？
好きに解釈しやがれ｡
Think what you will.
いいから早く言えってん…｡
Just tell us already.
え？ 何これ？
なにやってんの このからくり｡
Huh? What's this?
What's this robot doing?
Hey, what's it...
ねぇ なにやって…｡
ｷﾞｯ ｷﾞｬｱｰｯ！
銀ちゃ～ん！
Gin-chan!!
なっ なな
なにやってんですか 源外さん｡
Wh-Wh-What are you doing, Gengai-san?!
こ これ 命かけるっていうか…｡
Th-This is more than just risking his life!
これもう銀さん これ これ～！
Th-This means Gin-san's...
This... This is...!
え？
え なにこれ？
Huh? What's this?
誰これ？ やだこれ｡
Who is this?
I don't like this.
G-Gengai-san?!
源外さん｡ なんですか これ？
What is this?!
なんで銀さんが
こんなにちっちゃくなってんで…｡
Why is Gin-san so tiny?!
打ち出の大槌Ｚ503型｡
The magic mallet Z503.
[Note: Parody of legendary Japanese
hammer, Uchide-no-Kozuchi.]
打ちつけた対象物に
超電磁波を送り➡
It sends super magnetic waves
through the object it hits
なんやかやで細胞を縮小し
対象物を小さくする｡
and shrinks the target's cells
and the target itself.
A high-tech weapon created by yours truly.
ｵﾚ作 超科学兵器だ｡
ｳｿですよね｡ 違いますよね？
まさかそれ ﾎﾞｸらにも…｡
You're joking, right?
I'm wrong, right?
Don't tell me you're going
to smash us with...
やめろ！ これ以上罪を重ねるな！
S-Stop!
Don't add to your crimes!
そんなことをして
なにになるというんだよ｡
What can you possibly accomplish
by doing this?!
いったい なんのためにこんな…｡
Why are you doing this?!
Shouldn't that be obvious?
決まってんだろ｡
ｳｲﾙｽを駆逐するんだよ｡
We're going to eliminate the virus.
ｳｲﾙｽﾜｸﾁﾝでも ｳｲﾙｽﾊﾞｽﾀｰでもねえ｡
Not through a vaccine or an anti-virus.
ﾃﾒｴら 一寸法師が…｡
You midgets are doing it.
幸運を祈る｡
Best of luck to you.
You jerk!
ぎゃ～っ！
(神楽)ｵﾆ～！
銀さん｡ そろそろ
交代してくんないですか｡
Gin-san.
Can we trade off already?
Don't give me that crap.
ふざけんな｡
さっき代わったばっかだろ｡
We just switched.
若いうちの苦労はな…➡
Once you're old,
you'll be willing to buy back the hardships
during your youth at a Book-Hoff.
[Note: Parody of Book Off, a
chain of used bookstores.]
ﾌﾞｯｸﾎﾌで買ってでもしろ
って言うだろ｡
中古でもいいんだよ｡
Even if they're used.
ﾊｧ…
ｵｲﾙって こぐの異様に疲れるｱﾙ｡
It's extremely tiring to row through oil.
腹減ったね｡
食いｶｽでも 流れてないｱﾙか｡
I'm hungry.
You think any half-eaten
food will float by?
いや…
からくり ごはん食べないから｡
No, robots don't eat food.
今 どのへんｱﾙか？
Where are we right now?
口から入ったから
たぶん胃のあたりかな｡
We entered through her mouth,
so we're probably somewhere
around the stomach.
Does a robot even have a stomach?
つ～か からくりに
胃なんてあんの？
知らないです｡
そもそもさ…➡
I don't know.
Where are we even headed
to begin with?
ｵﾚたち いったい
どこに向かってんの？
知らないです｡
知らねえじゃねえだろ！
I don't know.
How can you not know?!
What are we supposed to do?!
ど～すんだよ ｵｲ！
いきなり ｳｲﾙｽ倒せとか➡
He turns us into midgets all of a sudden,
tells us to defeat the virus,
一寸法師にされて
機械の口に放り込まれてよ…｡
and throws us into her mouth?!
ｵﾚたち ｳｲﾙｽの倒し方も➡
We don't know how to defeat
the virus or where it even is!
ｳｲﾙｽが どこにいるのかも
知らねえんだぜ｡
ﾎﾞｸにあたらないでください｡
全部 源外さんのせいです｡
Don't take it out on me.
This is all Gengai-san's fault.
ﾁｯ… あんのｸｿｼﾞｼﾞｲ！
That stupid old man...
なんで ﾎﾞｸだけ２回…｡
Why am I the only one with two?
どうだ｡
名づけて ｢一寸法師計画｣｡
Well?
I call it Operation Midget.
まんまｱﾙ｡ ﾋﾈﾚよ｡
That's so bland.
Use a little more imagination.
お前たちは これから
たまの体内に入り➡
You're going to enter Tama's body
and treat her from the inside.
内側から直接
治療行為を始めるのじゃ｡
あの～… そんなこと言われても➡
Uh...
We don't know anything about
robots, so what do we do?
ﾎﾞｸら からくりの知識もないのに
どうすれば…｡
I was expecting you to ask that.
そういうと思ってな…
これを使え｡ ほれ｡
Use these. Here.
Isn't this just a toothpick?!
ただの爪楊枝じゃねえか！ ｼﾞｼﾞｲ！
Old geezer! You sure you didn't
just want to play with midgets?!
これ お前が 一寸法師ごっこ
やりてえだけだろうが！
ただの楊枝と思うな｡
ちゃんと改造してある｡
Don't mistake those for
ordinary toothpicks.
They've been modified.
銀の字
その楊枝の柄を押してみろ｡
Gin-no-ji, push on the base
of your toothpick.
あっ？ だいたい ﾃﾒｴの改造は➡
Eh?
Like we can count on your modifications
to be worth anything.
あてにならねえんだよ｡
前だって…｡
The last time...
((銀の字 木刀の柄を押せ！
Gin-no-ji! Push on your
wooden sword's grip!
たぁ～っ！
醤油が出る｡
だから なんで醤油だ!?))
It dispenses soy sauce.
So, why soy sauce?!
安心しろ｡ ｵﾚの技術は
あの頃より 格段に上がってる｡
Don't worry.
My technical skills have
improved since then.
思いっきり 押してみろ｡
Go ahead. Push it.
ﾁｯ… あんま期待できねえが…｡
Tch, I'm not expecting anything...
いってみっか～っ！
But I'll give it a shot!
ﾀﾞｼ醤油だ｡
何の技術が上がってんだ ｸｿｼﾞｼﾞｲ！
It's dashi soy sauce.
[Note: Dashi is bonito fish stock.]
How have your technical skills
improved, stupid old geezer?!
ﾋｬｯﾎｰ！ 卵かけごはんが
もっと うまくなるね｡
Woohoo! My egg rice will be tastier now!
うるせ～！
お前が醤油のﾀﾞｼになれ!!
Shut up! You turn into soy sauce!
四の五の言ってねえで 行くぞっ！
Stop griping and get going.
(３人)うわっ！
ｵｲ！ なんで お椀!?
やっぱ ﾃﾒｴ…➡
Hey! Why a bowl?!
You just want to play with midgets!
一寸法師ごっこ
やりたいだけじゃねえか！
雰囲気は大事だろ｡
It's important to have atmosphere.
何か ここ ﾈﾊﾞﾈﾊﾞするね｡
It's all sticky.
これ きっと たまさんの体内に
入りやすくするため➡
This must be some kind of special
coating to make it easier
何か 特殊なｺｰﾃｨﾝｸﾞされてる…｡
to enter Tama-san's body...
ｵﾚが さっき 納豆食べてた椀だ｡
It's the bowl I just used to eat natto.
[Note: Natto is fermented soybeans.]
いい加減 しばきますよ ｱﾝﾀ！
I'm gonna strangle you!
口から行くぞ！ じゃ 健闘を祈る｡
You'll be going through the mouth.
Godspeed, you three.
うわ～っ！
あのｼﾞｼﾞｲ！
Damn old geezer...
こんな爪楊枝１本で
何ができるんだよ！
What are we supposed
to do with a toothpick?!
It can't even remove the squid
stuck between my teeth...
こんなもん 歯に挟まったｲｶさえ
取れやし… あっ取れた！
Hey, it got it.
意外に使えた｡
ありがとう じいさん｡
It's actually useful!
Thanks, old geezer!
なんて言うか ﾎﾞｹ！
ｸｿｼﾞｼﾞｲ 死ね！
Like I'm actually going to say that!
Die, you damn old fart!
ｲｶを ﾉﾄﾞに詰まらせて死ね！
Choke on some squid and die!
Pulling out some Do***mon-esque
gadget and shoving us into hell!
[Note: Parody of Doraemon.]
いきなり
｢…えもん｣みたいな道具出して➡
人を地獄に
叩き落としやがってよ！
If I ever get out of here, I'm going inside
him and exiting through his urethra
ここから出たら
絶対 今度ｱｲﾂの中に入って➡
爪楊枝 素振りしながら
尿道通って出てきてやるよ！
while slashing this toothpick around!
はいはい
ｸﾞﾁは そこまでにしましょう｡
Yeah, yeah. That's enough whining.
This is the only way to save Tama-san.
たまさん救うには
これしか方法ないんですから➡
どっちみち
やるしかないんですよ｡
We don't have a choice.
That's right.
そうね｡
虎穴に入らずんば虎子を得ずｱﾙ｡
Nothing ventured, nothing gained.
ﾉﾄﾞﾁﾝｺ通らなきゃ
ﾁﾝｺには たどり着かないｱﾙ｡
You can't reach the urinary uvula
without passing through
the palatine uvula.
いや たまさんには
ついてないからね｡
Uh, Tama-san doesn't have one.
But her name means "balls."
たまなのにｱﾙか？
しつけえよ!!
Get over it!
あっ 陸が見えてきたね！
ここって どのへんだろう？
I can see land!
I wonder where we are.
口から入って
胃を通ってきたから➡
We entered through the mouth and
passed through the stomach,
小腸の入り口辺りじゃないかな｡
so we're probably near the entrance
to the small intestine.
つうか からくりに小腸なんて
あんの？
知らないです｡
Does a robot even have
a small intestine?
I don't know.
ﾎﾝﾄに大丈夫なのかよ？
Will this really work?
とりあえず あちこち
探索してみるしかないですね｡
We'll just have to look around.
小腸 入って 肛門のほうまで
行ってみましょう｡
We can enter the small intestine
and head towards the anus.
つうか
からくりに肛門なんてあんの？
And does a robot even have an anus?
知らないです｡
しようがないでしょ｡
I don't know.
We don't have a choice.
情報収集するにも 人なんて
こんな所にいるわけな…｡
It's not like we can gather information when
there aren't any people around...
いた～！ 人いた～!! なんで!?
There's one!
There's someone here!
Why?!
なんで たまさんの体内に
人がいるんだよ！
Why is there a person inside Tama-san?!
つうか なんで
全身ﾀｲﾂはいてんだよ！
And why is he wearing a bodysuit?!
よくわからねえが 地獄に仏だ｡
いろいろ聞いてみよう｡
I don't really get it, but I'll take
whatever I can get right now.
We can ask him.
ちょ ちょっと待って！
銀さん危ないですよ！
Hold on!
Gin-san! It's dangerous!
あのう すみません｡
Uh, excuse me.
あのう
お休みのところ悪いんですが➡
Uh, sorry to disturb your nap,
but I need to ask a few questions.
ちょっと
お伺いしたいことがありまして｡
Uh, do you live here?
あのう
こちらにお住まいの方ですか？
We're on a company trip and
this is our first time here,
ﾎﾞｸら ちょっと社員旅行で
ここ初めて来たんですけど➡
勝手がわからなくて｡
so we don't know our way around.
あのう すみません｡
Uh, excuse me...
ｹﾂに矢刺さってますけど
大丈夫ですか？
There's an arrow sticking
out of your rear...
Are you okay?
あぁ旅の人よ｡
Greetings, travelers.
いまわの際に
再び人に会えるとは運がいい｡
Fortune must be smiling on me to bring me an
encounter with you as I lie on my deathbed.
いまわの際って
ｹﾂに矢刺さってるだけですけど｡
Lie on your deathbed? You just
have an arrow in your ass.
Please listen to my last request.
どうか死にゆく私の最後の頼み
聞いてもらいたい｡
いや その前にｵﾚの話聞いて｡
ｹﾂに矢刺さってるだけだって｡
Uh, could you listen to me first?
It's just an arrow in your ass.
我が王に言づてを頼みたいのだ｡
I bequeath you to carry
a message to my king.
王？
King?
残念ながら ｳｲﾙｽ軍を前に
我ら白血球軍は壊滅｡
It saddens me to say that
our leukocyte army
has fallen to the virus army.
じき この世界は
ﾔﾂら獏の手に落ちるでしょう｡
This world will soon fall into
the hands of the Tapir.
願わくば 王だけでも➡
I pray that our king takes flight.
ここからお逃げいただきたい｡
そして 古くから伝わる
伝説の異界の戦士➡
And searches for the legendary
warriors from another world...
一寸法師を お捜しくださいと…｡
Search for the midgets...
[To Be Continued]
[A Little 3-Z Ginpachi Sensei]
A Little
Ginpachi Sensei!
Uh, we have a question from
someone with the pen name
Cherry Blossom Samurai.
Hello.
I'm having a hard time drawing
Gin-san's dead fish eyes.
Please tell me if there's a trick to it.
Okay. Here's your answer.
Basically, you need to separate
the eyebrows from the eyes.
And draw heavy eyelids.
You should only be able
to see half of his pupils.
Okay, all done.
Then you bring the eyebrows
and eyes closer together
and sharpen the eyelids.
There you go. A serious-looking Gin-san.
Okay, Cherry Blossom Samurai.
Stop trying to escape the lecture
by doodling in class.
[Preview]
Hey!
There's an RPG world
inside Tama's body?!
Why do leukocytes, white blood cells,
have a king?!
Why does this look so much
like Dragon Quest?!
I don't know.
The next episode...
"The Human Body is Like
a Little Universe!"
[An RPG world of anti-leukocyte viruses
has emerged within Tama's body.]
え～ ﾍﾟﾝﾈｰﾑ
桜色の侍さんからの質問｡
[Gin-san and the gang set out for the castle
in order to meet with the Leukocyte King.]
はじめまして｡
銀さんの死んだ魚のような目が➡
上手く描けません｡
ｺﾂがあったら教えてください｡
[See you next time.]
はい ｽﾞﾊﾞﾘお答えします｡
基本 まゆ毛と目までの距離を
離してください｡
で まぶたは重たそうに｡
瞳は下半分くらいしか
のぞいてません｡
はい 完成｡
で この
まゆ毛と目の距離を近づけ➡
まぶたも ｷﾘｯとさせると…｡
はい ｼﾘｱｽ銀さんになります｡
じゃあ 桜色の侍➡
授業中の現実逃避の落書きは
ほどほどにするように｡